Kenan Bölükbaşı

Керан Андреев Давидов | Keran Andreev Davidov

Game Developer & Designer, CG Generalist, Architect

	İstanbul - Turkey
C	+ 90 (542) 5362620
8	KENANBOLUKBASI
	KENANB@6x13.com
	KENANBOLUKBASI@GMAIL.COM
②	☑ KENANB.COM ☑ 6x13.COM 🏛 BFCT
1	Mobile: 🛊 🛊 📕 🐧 Desktop: 🖵 🙎
<u> </u>	♥ KENANBOLUKBASI 🔊 BLOG.6x13.COM
	© KENANB © 6x13

SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS

Theoretical and applied knowledge in programming, design and media. Broad experience in project management. Experience in 3D (mesh, solid & CAD), 2D (raster, vector), and parametric graphics as well as asset pipelines and tools development. Blender 3D specialist (Blender Foundation Certified Trainer).

PERSONAL DETAILS

EU (Bulgarian), Turkish CITIZENSHIP **B** Class DRIVER'S LICENCE DATE & PLACE OF BIRTH 28th January 1987, Bulgaria

EDUCATION

2005 - 2017	Architecture (B.Arch.) Istanbul Technical University, ITU School of Architecture, İstanbul
2001 - 2005	High School (Science and Math) Nilüfer Milli Piyango Anatolian High School, Bursa

CONFERENCES & WORKSHOPS

Talks & Lectures

2017	Introduction to Modern Computer Graphics ITU School of Architecture, Taşkışla, İstanbul
2016	Toxicity in Gaming: Negative Effects of Prioritizing Player Motivation in World Design ITU School of Architecture, Taşkışla, İstanbul
2014	Prototyping & Optimizing Game Asset Workflow Blender Conference, Amsterdam
2014	Automated Sprite Rendering System in Blender Libre Graphics Meeting, Leipzig
2014	Blender Python Programming Workshop BlendFX Studios, Leipzig
2011	AudioSpaces LiveCoding Workshop ITU School of Architecture, Taşkışla, İstanbul

2015	Game Developers Conference EU 2015 UBM Tech, Cologne
2013	Python İstanbul Meetings İstanbul
2011	IAF Compositing Workshop Özgür Gülbir, İstanbul

WORK EXPERIENCE

6x13 Games, İstanbul

JAN 2015 - [CONT'D]

Founder, Project Leader & Developer

Project leader. Game design and development. Graphic design and game asset creation. Prototyping, pipeline optimization.

- Game design, game & level editor development, project lead, graphics and user interface design of TWINIWT, the innovative, free to play symmetrical movement puzzle. Globally featured on both AppStore and Play Store.
- Project management & development of 1FPS GAME SERIES. 4 free to play handheld console games. The titles are:

- 1FPS: INVADERS - 1FPS: VACUUM - 1FPS: FASTFOOD - 1FPS: GRAFFITI[WIP]

- Cocos2d-x based in-house cross-platform game framework.
- Design, development and artwork of WRECKJUMPER[WIP], forced-perspective sci-fi TBS with dynamic puzzle elements.
- Data structure design and development of the visualization module for an architectural research project, FAÇADE, at ITU. It generates facades using evolutionary algorithms.
- Development of Fossicker, open source asset prospector.
- Guest lecturer for M.Arch., M.Sc. in Design Computing courses and B.Arch. design studios at ITU.

EKSERIYA STUDIOS, İSTANBUL Aug 2013 - Jan 2015 Graphics Department Lead & TD

Decision making on graphics technology and workflow. Workflow optimization software development. Game asset creation, shading and lighting. Pipeline integration and prototyping.

- · Asset pipeline automation system (import, lighting, rendering, compositing & atlas) for mobile RTS, SILICON WARS.
- Environment art and map editor for RIOT DEFENSE game.
- Pseudo 3D graphics R&D for FOOTBALL WIZARD game as-

FREELANCE, İSTANBUL

JUN 2011 - FEB 2014

Visualization Artist

Archviz for various firms. Modeling & rendering of office furniture catalog of Bürosit as well as indoor visualizations.

EFOR EVENTS & SIMMETRICO, BAKU AUG 2011 - SEP 2011 Assistant Site Manager

Construction site management of a large steel structure for the wedding event of Azerbaijani President İlham Aliyev's daughter, in a multinational (Italian, Turkish & Azerbaijani) environment.

EFOR EVENTS, İSTANBUL

JUL 2010 - APR 2013

Event Supervisor

Workflow & stage manager. Major events: Windows 8 Turkey Launch, Kenan Doğulu concert, VIP trip to Czech Republic. Clients: Microsoft, TeliaSonera, Huawei, Volvo, Doğuş, Soyak.

ASCIOĞLU İNSAAT, İSTANBUL

SEP 2009 - Nov 2009

Assistant Site Manager, Internship

Application supervision at Acıbadem Hospital building of Selenium Twins (BJK Süleyman Seba Complex) construction site.

ALPO ENGINEERING, İSTANBUL

MAR 2007 - MAY 2007

3D Artist

Technical drawings, archviz, urban planning modeling.

PROJECTS & RECOGNITION

PROGRAMMING PROJECTS

2017 Twiniwt Mobile Game, 6x13 Games

An innovative symmetrical movement puzzle. Globally featured on the AppStore Puzzle and Board categories, as well as Play Store Indie Highlights and Indie Corner. It works on all popular mobile and desktop platforms. Uses modified Cocos2d-x game engine, C and C++.

2016 1FPS Retro Game Series, 6x13 Games

4 games that work on all popular mobile and desktop platforms. Uses customized Cocos2d-x and C++.

2015 Fossicker, The Asset Prospector, 6x13 Games

An asset generator that regexp over asset name to create relevant dummies. Powerful plugin system relies on CLOS and Context Oriented Programming.

2014 Riot Game Map Editor, Ekseriya

Map editor, importer/exporter that lets users both define and tile assets on a grid, export & raytrace the scene. Uses Blender Game Engine and Python.

2013 Sprite Automation System, Ekseriya

A system for automated game asset creation workflow. Uses Python, Blender3D (BPY) and Bash.

2013 **Hy Programming Language Blender Integration**Blender Python Module that adds HyLang support

2012 **CL-IES**

Common Lisp parser/reader and writer for IESNA LM-63 Photometry Standard files.

and lets users interactively script Blender using Hy.

2011 TwitGraph

CL bubble diagram generator. Searchs & visualizes relationships among a #hashtag and its neighbours.

DESIGN PROJECTS

- 2016 **ITU Architecture Program Senior Design Project**Habitation for Syrian refugees, with a focus on integration and employment, in Süleymaniye, İstanbul.
- 2014 **StumpWM Window Manager & HyLang Logos**Winner of StumpWM Official Logo Design Contest.
 Official logo design of Hy Programming Language.
- 2010 Nooka International Watch Design Competition
 Participation with Nooka Ploog-In Design

COMMUNICATION SKILLS

ENGLISH

- Listening: C2 (Mastery)*
 Reading: C2 (Mastery)*
- Spoken Interaction: C2 (Mastery)*
 Spoken Production: C1 (Advanced)*
- Writing: C2 (Mastery)*
- Prep Class Nilüfer Milli Piyango Anatolian High School Technical English – ITU Academic Essay Writing – ITU Research Paper Writing – ITU
- Work experience in Baku in a multinational environment for a month. Ensuring communication among Italian, Turkish, Azerbaijani and other parties.

Work experience in Prague for two weeks.

Guidance to several VIP clients including top government officials and corporate executives.

Constant interaction with foreign English speakers via technical/social platforms and mail.

TURKISH

- Native Speaker
- (*) Common European Framework of Reference for Languages

SOFTWARE SKILLS

[♥ USE | ⟨ > MODIFY | ► TEACH]

GRAPHICS SOFTWARE

00000		Blender 3D
00000		Inkscape
00000		GIMP
00000	>	ImageMagick, FFMpeg
0000		AutoCAD, DraftSight
		3D Studio Max, Maya

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

0000		C / C++
00000		Common Lisp, Scheme
00000		Python, Factor
00000		UNIX / Shell
		Lua, HTML5

DEVELOPMENT TOOLS & LIBRARIES

00000		Emacs
0000		Visual Studio
0000		GCC, Clang, MSBuild
0000		GDB, LLDB, Valgrind
		Make, CMake, Gradle
00000		Git Version Control System
00000		Cocos2d-x Game Engine (C++)
		Xcode, Android Studio

OPERATING SYSTEMS

00000		GNU/Linux (Arch, Debian)
00000		Windows XP/7/8/10
0000		macOS

DOCUMENTATION UTILITIES

		T _E X / L ^A T _E X Systems
00000		Doxygen, Org-Mode, Pandoc

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

HOBBIES	Blogging, Literature, Charcoal Drawing
COMMUNITIES	Free / Libre & Open Source Software, Blender Network, Lisp Game Development, IGDA, Factor Language Development

